Contact

5853556146 (Mobile) ruzansasuri@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ruzan-sasuri (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

PostgreSQL

TypeScript

Debugging

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

Ruzan Sasuri

Software Engineer | Security Initiatives | Performance Optimization San Francisco, California, United States

Summary

A Software Engineer with over 8 years of experience building, testing and maintaining product features. I am also an avid gamer and like to build fun side projects. Please visit my website https://ruzansasuri.com to see some of my work.

Experience

F5 Networks Software Engineer March 2019 - December 2024 (5 years 10 months) Remote

- Led full-stack development for customer-facing features on a large-scale platform, working with product, UX/UI, and engineering teams to deliver scalable solutions. Developed a multi-provider VM provisioning feature and mentored junior developers to enhance productivity and foster a collaborative environment.
- Implemented caching mechanisms to reduce load times of schemagenerated pages from 60 seconds to 2 seconds, significantly improving user experience and system performance.
- Contributed to security initiatives as part of the Security Ninjas program, writing and reviewing Threat Model Assessments for new and existing features, enhancing product security by identifying and addressing vulnerabilities during the design phase, reducing the risk of post-release security flaws.
- Improved testing efficiency and collaboration by integrating Cypress into CI/CD pipelines for automated UI testing, increasing test coverage, and reducing manual QA efforts, while also promoting Test-Driven Development (TDD) and mob-programming practices to reduce post-release defects by 30% and accelerate development cycles.

Accenture
Software Engineering Analyst
November 2013 - April 2016 (2 years 6 months)
Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

- Deployment and creation of scripts (Perl and Shell) in order to enhance the automation process and help with disaster recovery in case of a server failure.
- Major focus on automation of various aspects of U2L (Unix to Linux) migration, including transferring configuration files and binaries using Shell and Perl scripts.
- Used Perl/CGI, HTML, CSS and Javascript to create web pages to help read server data on a web page.

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology

Master's Degree, Computer Science · (2016 - 2018)

Thakur College of Engineering and Technology
Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Computer Engineering (2009 - 2013)

Cathedral and John Connon School I.S.C., Science (2007 - 2009)

Cathedral and John Connon School I.C.S.E., Science · (1996 - 2007)